HUSEIN KAREEM

SUMMARY

I'm an iOS Developer with over 5 years of native development experience. I develop apps primarily in Swift but sometimes have to get my hands dirty with Objective-C code. Over the years I've worked with most of the common Apple frameworks like CoreData, CoreLocation, MapKit, UIKit along with other 3rd party libraries. I'm flexible in all work environments and have delivered products independently as a freelancer and in large Agile Scrum teams.

EXPERIENCE

Northwestern Medicine, Chicago - iOS Developer

DEC 2019 - PRESENT

Joined the myNM team to work on improving the app experience and design for our over 300,000 mobile users. Helped lead the transition to bring the project in-house from PWC and developed testing practices for stable future releases. Developed in Swift and heavily coupled with Epic's MyChart library.

United Airlines, Chicago - iOS Developer

JUNE 2019 - SEPT 2019

I was contracted to work on an internal app called Voices for United Airlines. The app allows employees to submit incident reports on/off aircraft. Responsibilities included: attending development meetings to assist 3rd party firms in estimating development/re-design efforts along with assessing the current situation of the app. Short-term contract, low-development, Swift.

The Rezi, Chicago — Lead Software Engineer/Co-Founder

AUG 2018 - JUNE 2019

Developed an internal application to keep track of deliveries and notifying users of package notifications. Focus on delivering SASS tools and applications for companies dealing with moving logistics. The back-end is built with Ruby on Rails and the internal mobile application built natively on iOS (Swift). The product is mostly defunct with some remaining uses left for a Chicago startup called Marketsquare.

FastModel Sports, Chicago — Software Engineer

FEB 2018 - AUG 2018

I built and managed 3 iOS applications (Swift, Objective-C) and 1 Android application using Flutter. Responsibilities Included: recruiting and interviewing mobile developers to grow the team. Also worked on the front-end

Angular JS and Shopify site. Implemented testing practices for all mobile applications.

BMW Group, Chicago - iOS Developer

OCT 2017 - FEB 2018

Joined as a contractor to build features for the BMW Connected Drive App. Primarily worked with the business products team. Most of my time here was spent building a share extension for BMW/MINI car owners leveraging ShareKit and writing a whole lot of Unit/UI Tests. Written in RXSwift.

SpotHero, Chicago – iOS Developer

APR 2016 - SEPT 2017

Joined SpotHero along with my former Director @ my previous employer. The goal was to start implementing testing, distribution, and development of the mobile app so that we can grow the iOS team. Converted app from 100% Objective-C to nearly 100% Swift. Led the development of a parking SDK that is used by Hertz.

Vokal, Chicago - iOS Developer

AUG 2015 - FEB 2016

Joined as a full-time developer and worked on a variety of applications in the fitness and e-commerce space.

EDUCATION

Mobile Makers Academy, Chicago

MAY 2015 - AUG 2015, Chicago

No Diploma, HS Diploma

Bitmaker Labs/General Assembly, Toronto

MAY 2014 - AUG 2014, Toronto

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Kennesaw State University, Marietta

AUG 2012 - MAY 2014, Marietta

No Diploma, HS Diploma

SKILLS

Swift. Objective - C. Xcode. Git. Core Data. UIKit. REST. MapKit. Core Location. Networking.